[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
Tesla on today's episode we're hot on
the heels of last week's categorization
of AI tools session uh to talk about one
of the hottest topics that developers
are using with open arms or sometimes
just looking at using or maybe showing
great skepticism around we're going to
talk to you about how you can level up
your usage of code completion tools and
and how you can make sure that the tools
you're using um are really set up
correctly and everything is available to
them to provide you with the best uh
suggestions possible and joining me on
this podcast is Peter guti president and
CMO at tab n welcome Peter thank you Sam
uh tell us a little bit about yourself
tell us a little bit about what you do
what president and CMO means at
tab9 I'll maybe I'll frame it with tab9
first so tab 9 is the originator of the
AI code assistant category and so tab9
as a business actually started back in
2018 when llms first emerged and it was
abundantly clear that these language
models if the language was highly
structured and repeatable and well
documented that it was very good at them
and what languages are more well
documented and repeatable than
programming languages so the company
released the very first both built-in
llm and an AI code assistant for Java
and operated as an independent business
for many years selling directly to
developers this was like the hidden
secret if you were a high performing
developer this is the kind of stuff you
had running in your IDE to make you a
little bit faster and to eliminate some
of the the mundane in the day-to-day for
you and as the llms emerged and kept
getting stronger and stronger all of a
sudden call it two and a half years ago
when chat gbt came out AI obviously has
been around for most of us been working
on it for seven eight years and then
what happened was all of a sudden with
gbt everybody understood what was
possible and then all of a sudden then
every CEO was asking every CIO what are
you doing what are you doing with AI we
have to be on top of this and so fear of
missing out they start pushing down and
what was pretty consistently used were
AI code assistants so I met the founders
of tab9 I'm a longtime interpress
software guy I uh I used to build apps
over the first 15 years of my career and
then the last 15 I've been in companies
like enginex built and scaled that
business super proud of my work in open
source most recently was at cockroach
Labs behind cockroach DB built that
business up and as the buyer for tab n
shifted from being the individual
developer swiping a credit cards all of
a sudden cios and heads of engineering
looking at this I was able to come on
join the founders and I help with go to
market strategy I help them think
through product strategy and really just
how the space is going to evolve and and
how we as a business adapt to support
our customers amazing and it must have
been such a roller coaster ride the last
few year last really probably four years
or sober over the last six years at T N
you were there before it was cool before
people were really talking about it and
it must have nice but it must have been
nice to effectively have a an already
running established business such that
when the hype came in and and everyone
started wanting to jump on this
bandwagon you're already there business
as usual and it was just a case of can
we execute to this to this to this
greater level of of Demand with people
trying to do that it's very true and
what's really remarkable is there's like
a there's a pretty dramatic evolution of
the species happening right now and it's
happening in sort of three ways like the
models themselves are getting stronger
and stronger we're all learning how to
use them better and what you realize is
the models themselves are not the answer
right it's all of the work we do around
it the app the UI all the prompt
engineering and all the context we feed
it and how we actually interact with the
model and the learning that we all are
going through is it's an incredible clip
like we are just we're discovering how
to get more and more out of these llms
and and more and more deliver more and
more value to the user yeah then
obviously as a business the customer is
pulling us in and that doesn't happen
very often I've built some great
companies over the years I've built some
great products over the years and many
times you're focused on a pain and
you're just really trying to get that
product out there Gardner estimated that
as of the end of last year only about
10% of enterprise software developers
were using these tools but they estimate
by the end of 2027 that number will be
almost 80% right right I've never seen
software adopt get adopted that fast
never in my whole career and weirdly you
think and weirdly you think in
2027 three years away you'd think why
are 100% of people not going to be using
this with the with the way the llms are
going to be growing and expanding it's
who who is this who is this one in five
developers that are not using something
like this because you think even if
you're not using it today which yeah
there are reasons why people might want
not want to use it today surely in three
years it's going to be so much more
improved as well because we've seen the
level of growth and the level of how the
llms have got better and more fine tuned
yeah it's it's a no-brainer right people
are going to be out of business if
they're not going to be doing this no I
agree and I think I would argue if
you're not using them today you have to
ask yourself why right I mean there are
there's enough variety and diversity in
the tool chain itself where you can have
incredible tooling that fits your
corporate standards right because the
only real question about two-thirds of
cios are concerned about data privacy
with Gen so they're very concerned about
shipping their most valuable data and
insight off to a third party and and
having it processed off site about a
third are concerned about copyright and
license infringement which also you know
pretty fair concern given all the stuff
that's unsettled copyright law with AI
right now however with this explosion of
investment we've all made in the last
five years you've got private models
you've got privately deployed versions
of AI code assistant like like tab n
you've got You've Got A diversity of
relationships you can have around the
models and what content it's trained on
you can even train TRS these code
assistance down on your own code instead
of having to worry about third party so
I feel like there's enough diversity and
these tools are incredibly powerful
incredibly powerful and if you think
about state-of-the-art 18 months ago or
maybe two years ago was simple code
completion as you typed right that was
state-of-the-art and it was pretty
remarkable right it's predicting the
function you're writing it's autofilling
classes and it's making you just work so
much faster yeah but then
state-of-the-art then even six months
later 12 months later was an an
assistant that you're chatting with
right now the state-of-the-art is these
code assistants that are that touch
every single part of the sdlc and they
know your code base and they know your
standards and they're actually even
interacting with you in a way that
behaves more like an onbord an engineer
on your team so where are we gonna be in
three years it's so to predict isn't it
yeah yeah I think the my belief on this
I've lived through a lot of these
transitions right and I think the change
for software development here is as
radical as the change went through
starting with no Version Control doing
everything local and then doing
everything waterfall and doing
everything on local machine compared to
the way we do it today where we've got
continuous integration continuous
delivery we got everything done in agile
we're doing everything in Cloud
infrastructure we're doing everything in
composable infrastructure like if you
took a software engineer in 1998 writing
web applications and then you dropped
them in 2018 and you showed them how
they did it they wouldn't even
understand what was happening it be so
confusing I think we're about to go
through the same thing with AI enabled
software development yeah and we
mentioned if there's 80% of people then
that's going to be on it in in in 2027
still 20% of people not there are a
number of reasons right I guess some if
you look today there are going to be
some people who's maybe their companies
are saying like we're going to put a
blanket ban on on AI tools for whatever
corporate reasons some devs are going to
love it some devs aren't going to love
it I guess some devs really those who
have really adopted it and embraced it
really levels up their productivity and
they see it as an assistant other devs
they think it's going to take their jobs
how do you reply how do you respond to
people who are like really concerned
that yes it's an assistant today but
where is it going to be tomorrow yeah
look I think the capability of these
things are getting stronger and stronger
and there there will be an evolution
that occurs we started with AI code
completion we're now at the tail end of
the era of what i' call AI assistance
and this is true not just for software
development but but other categories as
well but we're at the point into the
spere as software developers living
through these these
Transformations really right now we're
in what I call the AI agent era where
we've crafted the capabilities of these
AI agents to accomplish very specific
tasks but with full automation you think
about documentation you think about
testing we have ai agents that will
generate a test run the test return the
results and and help you understand what
code needs to change yeah that's a fully
contained agent and we will get to a
place of where eventually we have have
ai Engineers right where we just feed it
requirements and then it comes back with
a function or an application or
componentry and we'll do super rapid
iteration on those with that and so I
think what I'd say for those who are
concerned is yeah the reality is your
job is going to change I think though
the concern that AI is going to take
your job is is fairly overblown right I
think it fairly overblown what we
actually see in the people who use AI
assistance the best
is it levels them up instead of having
to be in the weeds blocking and tackling
executing specific things they get to
think more like Architects they get to
think more like designers right where
they're really looking saying what's the
construction of this application how do
I want it interact and I think that
happens pretty regularly with Automation
in almost every job function in software
development you think about like for
those of us who started our careers in
the 90s people used to write memory
management in their application right
does anyone listening to this podcast
even understand how to do memory
management probably not right we think
about when we first started building web
applications where we had to do a ton of
work around networking we don't think
about the Network anymore right all that
stuff is fully resolved for us and I
think the this is going to be a probably
an order of magnitude of a bigger change
than those examples but I think they're
going to be very similar right where if
you're somebody who is a systemic
thinker and you're thinking about the
components of an application you think
about you have dozens or hundreds of
microservices those microservices need
to interact with each other you're still
going to do that you're still going to
think that way it's Outsourcing is going
to be done for you by the machine yeah
you're still an app creator you're still
creating a solution but you're not
necessarily doing that the writing of
the code which arguably is as as uh my
co my co-host on this podcast when we
chatted last week coding is still a
small amount of the job you not as much
as we love to think a developer going to
sit in their IDE for five six hours a
day that's not always the case and
there's lots of other things that need
to be done around that and and a number
of developers that are using coom
completion tools who are more skeptical
of the code completion tools some people
try it and they say I think this is more
maybe the more senior devs who know what
to expect or know what they want in
terms of implementing something that
they're trying to achieve they say okay
this The Styling is wrong or I would do
it this way this is a more performant
way and actually they know very
specifically what they want from the
implementation and if they don't get
that maybe first second third go then
they think this isn't a an efficiency
play for me at all it's actually more
frustrating for me is this something you
hear from developers is there something
that happens yeah and and I think
there's I think there's a there's a bit
of truth to it right at the end of the
day you know if you're if you've got
very firm and specific expectations of
the structure of the code and the
specific uses that reuses from existing
code and things like that then yeah I
think these tools can feel a little
frustrating at times and I I think there
is a the thing for your listeners to
wrap their head around though is it
really does come down to the tool itself
then at that point because I think a lot
of people's experience with these tools
were not actually using the tools right
they were not using a code assistant
instead they were just going and and
putting in coding questions into a
chatbot right and what you end up with
is an ignorant genius when you do that
right these things it's like when you
start talking one of these chat Bots
about software development it's like
somebody who read a book on software
development right and so they're just
going to they're going to parot back
what they understand from what they read
but that's not in the right context
right even the most rudimentary code
assistants they're actually taking what
you're asking and they're doing prompt
engineering and and changes around that
to make sure that what you're actually
getting is useful in your use case and
then those of us who are really Advanced
like tab n and some others we also then
use a great deal of context and that's a
pretty dramatic change if you think
about I'm a car guy so forgive the
analogy if it doesn't resonate but if
you and I if you and I met on the street
and didn't know each other and you said
I heard you're a car guy what car should
I buy you i' give you a hundred answers
right and they're all academically
correct right but I don't know you I
don't know what your use case is so I'm
just going to give you a bunch of
options this is what Consumer Report
says and this is what the car Magazine's
like this is what Top Gear likes but if
you're my best friend and I know you
just had your third child and you're
really concerned about safety and you
really care about you know you really
concerned about climate change so maybe
I'm recommending a Volvo electric SUV
because I know you right and the code
assistants are no different if you ask
how to write a function in a language
and it doesn't know anything about you
it's going to give you something that
came out of an O'Reilly book right it's
going to give you something that's solid
right but it may not be relevant and
that's where I think senior JS get
frustrated however change it around now
give that same code assistant full
awareness of your codebase like we we
look at 18 different things just within
the IDE alone even before we hook in
through get to your Global codebase now
you ask that question and you're getting
something that's very specific to you
right says oh the way we write this
function is this way right we call this
API and that's a lot of the evolution
that that each of us are doing right now
because what we want is 100% acceptance
rate right we want you to interact with
the with the code assistant and have it
come back with something you're like
that's exactly what I meant right and we
have to shape the tools to be able to do
that I think we're I think we're pretty
dramatic just to give you a data point
on this s we added local codebase
awareness early this year right and we
just what we could access within the IDE
and in doing so our acceptance rate for
unaltered code that came back went up
40% just by reading what was open in the
IDE then we added in global codebase
awareness now we're adding in non-code
sources information then we're adding
standards and practices that are
documented in the company how specific
will we get we want that 100% acceptance
rate and your acceptance for unaltered
code there that means they're the
developer is accepting the the tab n
suggestion without making any changes
themselves without making any changes
exactly wow and that's 40% and so I
guess there's two 40% that's amazing and
I guess there's two that like when we
think about styling I guess there's two
almost aspects to it there's one is the
a very developer very specific style as
in I I prefer to use X versus Y and and
it's just the way that develop we go
back years with whole tabs and spaces we
can't even agree on that there's big
style questions then there's the
question of I want you to use
essentially the the like you say the
sdks the apis that we are using for the
rest of our projects and there is a way
that we write this code internally and I
think that second one is super super
important I think the first one is
actually if it gets done this way rather
than that way is it cosmetic versus
actually something more architectural or
structural and I think the the latter
piece which is using these other pieces
of our project don't try and reinvent
everything in different ways let's
architect this project this application
this this larger environment and let's
make sure we make good use of each of
those components and pieces
and so I think that's really interesting
because for me the Cosmetic piece is
take it or leave it if it gets done one
way that's fine if it gets done another
that that's equally fine and I wonder
when we think about that kind of style
is that even going to be important in
years to come because the more we dive
into the AI space who's actually reading
the code who's doing this is it going to
be other AI agents and Bots that
actually going to be doing that reading
that generating the tests the code
reviews and so forth and if that's the
case value does individual style
actually have if we are like you say
thinking more about it from that feature
by feature level versus the individual
lines of code any thoughts on that
breaking no yeah no I think you're you
hit a few things in there that I think
are really quite interesting and and
worth unpacking right the first and
foremost I think most of the earliest
generation of generative AI tools have
been focused on giving giving more and
more generation right more and more
knowledge able to do more and more
things but what we've discovered is
now we're at a point if we really want
to add value we actually have to make
them do more specific things like we
actually have to start constraining
right if anything we were we had gotten
to the point of where it's we could do
tons and tons of things it kept getting
smarter more more code could generated
more things could be automatically
generated but then now we're looking and
saying is it the right quality does it
meet our standards right is do do do we
apply our corporate policies against
that and we think that that's the next
evolution of the species here in this
right is constraints right we call it
coaching or expert guidance we have
actually in private preview right now
with our Enterprise customers we have
the ability for them to give us very
specific standards in plain English
right it doesn't we can read something
that was a document somebody wrote and
it's living in Confluence somewhere and
then use that to actually constrain
what's done and constrain it both in the
IDE so when things are formatting is a
good example we follow the Google Java
coding standards okay then that's how
the code is structured yeah that's what
it looks like so everyone can read it
right or even more more importantly
things like we never we never actually
talk to this API in this way because
it's security vulnerability so we just
don't do that right and we can also
catch it at code review so we can see it
when code is being pushed out and in in
reviews you're in the poll request and
says this violates the standards this
violates the standards this is what a
change looks like in order to adopt it
that to me is going to be really
transformative right because you think
about the process here you want to have
all these stand could be security could
be performance could be readability
could be all those things if we're not
actually evaluating the code validating
it before it goes out then we're in
trouble right and the best organizations
do that manually today AI can do this
incredibly quickly so that's a big one
and I think to your point around how
much is machine is readability of this
really going to matter I would actually
argue we're going to end up in a place
of where AI is actually generating a lot
of this code and generating actually
whole functions or whole applications
and if you really let them run and you
you have it optimized to meet your
standards it may not be human readable
right and and you think about what it
what it takes to actually make make code
run really fast right you you may make
some decisions in how the code is
structured in order to to optimize for
performance and then a human's going to
struggle to look at it so does that
matter if you have an AI generator AI
code generation happening then you have
ai code validation which is separate
different prompts different ways of
looking at it then the a will be able to
read it right it'll be able understand
what's going on so you don't have to
understand it right but you do have to
understand and this is I think really
critical if we're going to get to that
point of where it becomes less human
readable then you need to have absolute
trust that what the agents are doing
follows your standards and probably is
is held to a higher standard than the
humans are on your team today yeah very
interesting and and I think it's
actually if we draw a parallel um with
with
how software development has evolved
over time anyway people going from an
assembly language to a c compiler maybe
even to Java and actually okay now we're
compiling this to object code etc etc we
abstract ourselves away from the
instruction language and the bik code
Etc and when we think about it that way
when we think okay this this is
effectively an interpretation right if
I'm writing some Java source code and
that that compiles it into object code
is anyone actually looking at the bik
code looking at the loading stores Etc
when that goes down to an assembly
language is anyone actually thinking
about that and it's it's almost like a
mental hle to almost be comfortable with
abstracting ourselves away from that and
actually putting the trust in and and
perhaps that's one of the things like
it's that level of trust that we
generally need to get better at with AI
so long as we have the right guard rails
and things like that um going forward
one other one other point I'd love to
quickly make actually is um is one thing
which has always bugged me as a
developer which is when you look at a
project as that project grows people use
different packages and and different
they pull in different dependencies and
things when um they want to do the same
task and we've all been there where we
were sitting a project with five
different Jason paes and all this
because people don't understand or
people don't realize that other people
have had to do the same thing and have
already potentially pulled something in
or they do realize someone's potentially
pulled something in but they don't know
where to look they don't know they can't
find it and I think when we think about
a tool like tab9 for example that does
build that context around an entire
project and does use you know you know
that's going to be far more effective at
recognizing when I need to perform a
certain task if that task has been
performed in a similar way in my project
and use that same approach versus trying
to effectively recreate the wheel every
single time I want to do some basic core
functionality and I think that is is a
real value which is a pain point because
it grows our supply chain it messes up
the code in in terms of doing things in
different ways potentially having
different formats and so forth so I I
find that a really big value to to clean
the code up a little bit as well as you
know talking about what how readable it
is yeah no I think that's I think that's
right and I think this is the value of
what we call Global code based awareness
right so if the AI code assistant can
see your entire repo you know can see
everything that you're doing you can
optimize for things like reuse right you
can optimize things like um keeping your
volume of code down to a minimum right
by calling these functions repeatedly or
I think even when we think about
refactoring that a human pouring over an
entire codebase and trying to identify
where you have those issues where you've
Rewritten things that's a a hugely timec
consuming task and Nobody Does it right
Nobody Does it because we're we're we've
got too much on our plates to build the
next application or to fix something
that that has failed on us and so this
is exactly kind of thing we want to we
call about it we call about it
offshoring to silicone like we want to
actually push all of those things out to
the AI agents to do for us and
refactoring and restructuring code is
the kind of thing that it it's very good
at today and it's only going to get
stronger offshore offshoring to Silicon
is my new favorite phrase I'm gonna I'm
gonna make sure I use that every day now
I can't I
can't that's our CTO Iran yav he he's
been in deep learning and and automation
for developer tools for two decades
right and he he has this thing that's
effectively he calls it the fundamental
theorem of of automation which is the
amount of effort required to get a
system to interact the way you want it
to has to be lower than the amount of
effort would have taken just to do it
yourself so the offing it was always
that I could move things over to another
team I could Outsource this to another
place and you know AI up until just a
few years ago wasn't to the point of
where you could just do that and say
just delegate and and now you can and
it's getting better and better at that
degree of Delegation yeah one thing I
want to move us onto a little bit is is
more kind of things that we can have the
listeners take away in terms of what can
how can they improve both the likelihood
they're going to be successful with code
completion and also how they can change
the way they interact with these tools
and I want to start with I I guess when
we think of code completion tools there
are many code completion tools out there
obviously obviously you work for tab n
but I'd love to here maybe from a Maybe
from the tab 9 experience actually there
are going to be lots of tools that do
things differently and there will be
some better at certain things some
better at others from the tab n point of
view what are the core things which you
have found your users have really found
value in your platform in terms of
actually making them more successful a
great example there was that 40%
increase from the cont you say there are
certain things that that tab n have
learned from from this yeah well we I
mean I think about what these tools are
capable of today and what their
strengths are they're it's way more than
code completion now right it's already
truly an assistant throughout the sdlc
right we see them incredibly successful
in the obvious things of generating
functions right and generating component
as you're writing an application but
they're also incredibly good at
refactoring code identifying uh errors
and and defects right and you think
about where we spend most of our time we
don't spend most of our time writing new
code right we spend most of our time
actually in maintenance right and so
they're incredibly good at that you
think about refactoring or identifying
bugs or the the sort of mundane tasks we
have to go through when we're doing
updates and upgrades and we have to make
changes like they're really good at that
and that's something to lean into and
then they're incredibly good at these
sort of discreet AI agent tasks so like
tab n has an onboarding agent so when
you first open a new project or let's
say you're somebody who maybe worked on
that project quite some time ago and you
got how how it's structured it will walk
you through the project this is what it
does this is how it's structured this is
what it interacts with these are the
other systems that it talks to these are
the dependencies all the stuff that you
would have a senior engineer who works
on the project every day do with you so
it's really good at that it's really
good at things like automated test
generation automated
documentation so the their the guidance
I'd give to your listeners is look these
tools actually touch every part of what
you do and like instead of going to
search and going to try to find examples
of how to structure a certain function
or how somebody else solved a problem
you can actually just ask Tab n in the
IDE and it will come back with options
and actually come back with incremental
prompts like what else you should be
asking so you can do Discovery and I'd
encourage to just try it right there's
it's a new pattern it's a new way of
working you will discover very quickly
where it is great you'll also discover
very quickly where it's maybe not as
great you're also going to discover very
quickly how you have to interact with it
right I think as vendor ERS were very
focused on I want to understand the
intent of the developer and then I want
to structure the tool to respond so they
don't have to think about it they should
just be able to work the way they want
to work but there is a little bit of a
difference still with these things
around how you have to interact with it
versus maybe how you would put in a
Google search or how you would ask a
peer right they're a little bit
different Behavior today and so start
small start incremental try each of
these individual tasks and then start
pushing the boundaries and start
figuring out where they really perform
for you and it's like having a it's
truly like having a pair programmer
today it's like having somebody sitting
next to you you have to build that
relationship right you have to know what
it's going to be good at for you and
what how it fits the way you want to
work and I think that's a key takeaway
if you think you can just get in and
give it a a requirements document it's
going to spit out Perfection and you
probably have inflated expectations yeah
yeah and and you mentioned the kind of
like different agents and I've seen so
many good use of agents in in in the
industry and I think there people are
really leaning into the agents as a good
way of as a good way of performing
very specific different tasks um in
terms of the agents do you use different
models for the agents for different
tasks or is it is it just the kind of
like different backgrounds and different
goals and tasks that the agents are
trying to specifically do or is it a
mixture of the two So today we're not
changing models underneath each of the
agents we tab9 is one of just a couple
who actually have switchable models in
general so we have our own models that
we developed one that is fully private
and another one that is fully private
and also is only trained don't
permissively license code so there's no
security risk of copyright infringement
risk and then we have all the major
vendors we work with coher and we work
with anthropic and with open AI so you
can try it all what we've discovered is
for the most part the llms are reaching
if not commodity at least utility right
they're all converging towards the same
same level of performance where the
Agents come in basically the agent is
trained on a discrete task we've done
all of the prompt engineering and all of
the work in order to work through that
task and then we use specific context
and the specific context really matters
right because it's not enough for the
llm to respond you actually have to give
it appropriate framing for your problem
right and that appropriate framing
usually is something in how you work
something in the code base itself and
then it also needs to know what's a look
for like that onboarding agent is
actually doing you click a button that
says onboard me to this project but it's
actually doing a bunch of back and forth
with the llm and it's actually giving it
specific context from within the project
and it's it's got a vector database
behind it that actually has some of
these key characteristics so there's a
there's a a certain amount of sort of
app construction maybe is how i' think
about it just like you build an app
today you have to build all the logic
and you have to build the data that that
it works with and and how it responds
that's basically how these agents are
constructed and it's really powerful
right and I do think though at one point
either the models will end up being
being so similar that we won't worry
about do different agency different
models or we might actually make the
models a little bit smaller more
specialized for performance right and in
that case then yeah maybe we use a
slightly different model for each of
these things yeah and there's a debate
around some of that as well like what is
the right way forward and this is why we
have switchable and all these because we
want to experiment with all of it and
see what gives us the best performance
yeah it's interest it's interesting you
talk about the model size and things
like that because it's probably not
going to be long before we see models on
small devices very limited execution
power and things like that of course tab
n actually they offer you offer a an
offline mode as well right where you
kind of like run all that locally as
well as being able to use the service is
that developers use a lot or Edge case
well we have a number of customers who
are air gapped right so we tend to work
with large Enterprises who really make
privacy and security Paramount in what
they do and that's Banks it's
pharmaceutical companies it's
manufacturers it's anybody who's really
looking at saying I want to control
where the data goes and even we've
gotten more into government and defense
we work with for example one of the one
of the Departments of energy for
engineering part of the grid and things
like that that you cannot ever make
available on the open and those users
they like that right and so for us we
have
self-contained instances of tab 9
running in their private infrastructure
with its own models and it's fully air
gapped and on top of that we actually
had created our original code completion
models were on device so we actually
still have an on device model so if you
need to actually not even have the
laptop that you're working on connected
to something else we can do that and we
work with Intel and AMD and some of
these others and some of their
advancements and I think it's going to
be sooner rather than later that you're
actually able to run pretty sizable
models locally right and and we saw this
in other places right we saw this in in
in other areas of compute where we
thought everything would have to be on
some giant machine and when you think
about the the compute power on my phone
now is greater than supercomputers we
were running in the 90s and so I think
this idea of being able to actually have
functionality that's happening on device
versus in your private environment
versus requires cloud computing power
and all those things it's great that we
can actually tap into all of that
because the customer at the end of the
day needs to decide what is most
appropriate for their use case and as
vendors we need that degree of
flexibility to support that amazing
amazing it's amazing how fast it's
progressing like to think of the
possibility of having this on small
devices so quickly is mind-blowing so
let's talk about prompt engineering a
little bit as well in terms of how users
interact with with the model or with the
tool you're going to get I bet so much
variation in terms of people putting too
much not enough ambiguity in the
requests H how what advice would you
give to developers who are trying to
trying to give good or try to be more
effective in the responses that the tool
is going to provide them with short
succinct
messages yeah I have I'm of mixed
feelings on this because I do feel as
product developers on this we need to
actually meet the user where they are
and so like when you talk about prompt
engineering for the most part what we
try to do is in the ux actually
understand and interpret intention and
then that's what weage to go and
interact with both the model and with
our other agents and the goal there is
for them to not have to think about it
and say I ask that question badly let me
ask it a different way if you're a
regular user of chat GPT for example you
may actually restructure your query a
bunch of different ways because it's not
doing much in the way of interpretation
context there's some context if you
leave things open and you can feed it
some data but it's not like these other
generative AI tools that are built for
purpose like code assistance in those we
really are trying to understand if
you're asking a specific type of
question you've got a specific
application open specific files open I
see errors that have been generated in
the IDE I should be able to understand
all that and say okay what you're why
you're asking that question you really
want this and so that's the kind of
that's the kind of engineering that's
actually happening in these generative
AI tools right I think there a sort of
misunderstanding that if I just to make
a generative AI application I just need
an llm and call the API with a couple
questions all of a sudden I have an
application you have a pretty mediocre
application if you do that right May and
maybe an unsuccessful one the real
engineering comes around what we call
what we think of as a three-legged toool
yes you have a model right but then you
have to have really good prompt and
structure and good user experience to
understand in intention and to shape
that intention then into how you're
interacting with the model and then the
Third Leg of the stool is context right
right okay what else am I feeding into
the llm alongside those prompts to make
sure that I'm getting the correct answer
back and by correct not is it
academically correct but it's what you
meant it's what your intention was and I
think we're all working through that I
think what I would encourage your
listeners to do is if you're not getting
what you want in these interactions give
it more context use a tool like tab I
open the files that are relevant to that
so it can see them and it understands
what's going on or if you're trying to
do this through a third party tool that
doesn't allow you to do that copy and
paste additional context in right give
it some more detail and then try
expanding on your query right try
expanding on what you're asking for give
it more detail right it's just like a
human right if you're if you and I are
collaborating on a project and you're
looking for help the more context you
give me the more successful I will be
assisting you and we see the same exact
thing with gener of AI yeah and it's
interesting actually when we talk about
giving more like when I go to a
conference and I present for example I
know if I don't have one if I have more
than one point per slide let's say I
have three takeaway points from a slide
it'll be a really important one a less
important one and something that's
absolute that's just a story
that I made up they'll take away that
story and that'll be the thing that they
remember from that presentation or that
slide is there if you provide one thing
the audience or the llm will focus on
that thing is there a balance between
not enough too much yeah it's a great
call out it's there there is such thing
as too much context right because then
then it just doesn't understand what's
going on or it's just overwhelmed and
it's trying to understand okay how do we
weigh all of these things I think uh
larger and larger context windows and
more and more things that are fed in
what we we've not seen that actually
correlates with better outcomes what
instead we've seen is the right context
results and better outcomes and I think
that's something it's hard for someone
to do individually right it's hard for
somebody to to apply that themselves but
I think this is where we earn our money
right is actually understanding that so
like I said in the IDE we we touched
something like 18 different sources we
don't read all of it for every prompt
and every agent right we're using what's
appropriate in the agent you're going
and asking for a fix of broken code of
course we're going to read errors right
at some point we'll hook into
observability tools we can see actually
what's happening right in the
application and production right I'm not
going to go red documentation about
something and feed that when I'm trying
to fix code
right I have to keep it to a discreet
and finite thing it's just the way it's
just the way humans work think about
when you're starting a task what are the
things you want to have available to you
when you're starting that task what's
appropriate for what you're trying to do
that's a lot of the engineering we're
doing now is figuring out what are the
most appropriate things to leverage as
context yeah very interesting and I
think when we think about when we look
at code completion or AI just code code
generation in general we we can almost
drop into this Fantasy Land a little bit
where we' say look I'm I'm going to
write this one oneliner or or a short
prompt and I'm going to have this whole
application generated for me what do you
have advice in terms of the scale at
which we should be asking for things to
be generated should we be looking big
middle small what's really funny is I we
get feedback from our customers all the
time right and we're Relentless about
this we have a free product so we have
over a million monthly developers on our
free product wow these are like heavy
users this is not I think my total ID
downloads or something like 7 eight
million or something like that but these
are people who use it all the time right
they're constantly and so they're very
vocal about what works and what doesn't
and we had a hiccup with somebody who
was trying to do something that was
basically this super structured ask it
was basically trying to Output a python
app like that that that processed some
data and did some interpretation and
when I saw it come through I was like is
that even possible like they're they're
basically asking for something that is a
structured set of requirements that is
outputting a basically a complete
functioning sort of small application as
like a microservice and we had had some
hiccups which is why we had heard about
it but it was actually a connection
issue on their side that it wasn't
working once we fixed the connection ini
know on their side then it worked and I
was shocked like I was actually shocked
and I probably shouldn't be at this
point because I feel like the tools we
are get making them smarter and smarter
every day and I think I am equally
amazed and not when I see that happen I
do think though you don't want to start
start there right you don't want to take
a j ticket copy the whole thing in drop
it in and hope that it outputs the
entire functioning service I think there
are some of these discret things that
are absolutely working today we actually
have a prototype of what we call J to
code where literally just go in and it
takes a ticket and an outputs in this
case a JS app just fully functioning
with ux and everything but those are I
think still further apart so today start
with discret tasks start with things
like I need this function I need this
specific component that I'm trying to do
but then push the edges and see what it
will do and I think you might I I have
been surprised you might be surprised as
well yeah yeah and I think we we talk a
lot about training fine training and
fine-tuning llms and things like that
but a lot of it is really the other way
around as well we need to be better at
using these tools to get the most out of
these tools it's going to be it's going
to be something of a meeting in the
middle that where we really land right
because the like I said I I feel that we
have a responsibility as product
designers and developers to make sure
that it does just work the way you want
this is the whole point I started my
career and I remember all the debates
were do you even need goey right like
why aren't we just talking to the
computer in command line the way the
computer wants to be spoken to right
yeah and I always thought that was
ridiculous these are our machines right
we want them to behave the way we want
them to behave I think that is on us but
I think there's going to be some changed
Behavior here right there's going to be
new ways of working and just be open to
that right as a developer I feel like if
you've been a developer for any period
of time 10 15 20 years you've already
seen so much radical transformation in
your career in the last 20 years like
I've been building web apps since 94 and
it feels like it's a different Lifetime
and I think yeah AI is going to be some
radical change but we're good at that
like we as a we as a community are
really good at that we're always
constantly evolving anyway just be open
to the change and open to adapting it
and you will both get stronger and you
will also understand what requirements
we need to be we need to be responding
to as product developers as
well and finally let's take a look back
at where we are today in terms of
matching the hype with the actual
products and and capabilities and
Technologies are we at the are we at the
right level in terms of what we're
saying AI is today or how far are we
trading
behind uh it's a tough question because
I feel like it depends on who you talk
to I think the cheerleaders are doing
what they always do and they're probably
way more hyped up than what these things
are actually capable of today but it's
going to get there quickly can you
really call them wrong at the end of the
day I'm always I'm off I'm effectively a
sales and marketing guy that's really
what I am I have I've worked as an
engineer I've done enough of that but
I've always been a I've always been a
sales Mark guy right and my peers
frustrate me when I see them promising
things or overblowing what the thing is
actually capable of because I think it
diminishes your credibility right your
job and in technology and when you make
products like these is just to expose
the inherent truths of the product if
you do that then people will use it
people will buy it so I I do think the
hype train is a little much some days
with
Gen but then again we also keep matching
the expectation with reality in a very
short how long that's going to last but
it definitely is happening and then I
see the other side too I see a lot of
Skeptics who are who are like no these
things are garbage they don't really
work and I think that's also not correct
either right I think there's capability
in these tools one one of the things
that that I I was just reading is llms
are now effectively at the intellect of
a a grade schooler that's pretty
powerful right that's pretty great but
it's also the intellect of a grade
schooler that's that should frame your
expectations so there's some remarkable
capability which you should lean into
there's still a lot of room to develop
and grow which you should acknowledge
yeah absolutely it's the question of
would you let a grade schooler commit
code into your code
base obviously there's a difference
between the the smartness of of them the
pattern matching the correlation but
yeah there's there's certainly something
there that we can let so you know what's
really remarkable about that make that
comment is I think stack Overflow a few
years ago they do their normal developer
study and I remember reading you know
the number of people who they always
asked when did you write your first code
when did that come and actually the
highest performing developers started in
grade school so here we are so that
grade schooler that we've got as a code
assistant today is going to be a hell of
an engineer 20 years
ago looking forward to that amazing Peta
it's been absolutely great fun and very
good to to hear your and tab n's
opinions on cion thank you so much thank
you s appreciate the time
[Applause]
thanks for tuning in join us next time
on the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla
[Music]